Trice, Harrison M. Additional Papers /4164
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Harrison M. Trice Additional Papers
1973-1994
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Trice, Harrison M.
/4164
79.22 cubic feet
76.7 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Correspondence, personal subject files, publications, research projects, grant information, ILR school related files, and professional association documentation.
8017035
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 01, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 03, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Harrison Miller Trice served as a professor of organizational behavior in the School of Industrial and Labor Relations and a member of the Department of Sociology at Cornell University from 1955 until 1995. Through research and his publications, Trice became a catalyst in the prevention, detection, and treatment of occupational alcoholism. Building upon his results, Trice further developed and designed occupational alcoholism programs and frequently served as a consultant on the matter.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes correspondence between Trice and occupational alcoholism programs, personal subject files, research data and results, and teaching records spanning from 1941 to 1994. It documents the progression of Trice's research from fact-finding and historical accounts of job-based alcoholism programs to the development of preventive measures and organizational design. The collection highlights Trice's examination of civil service support, employee assistance programs, the role of occupational consultants and labor unions, and efforts of the Smithers Institute for Alcohol and Workplace Studies. A significant portion of the collection deals with individual occupational alcoholism studies and data results. The final section contains items related to the School of Industrial and Labor Relations and professional associations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4164 AV: Harrison M. Trice Audio-Visual Materials /3010: Harrison Trice Papers /4254: Harrison Trice Additional Books
Trice, Harrison Miller, 1920-; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8017035
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1952-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1968-1969, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Mailed material includes earlier published articles
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1969-1972, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1973, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes earlier written material
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1973 continued (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January-April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence May-June 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence July-September 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence October-December 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January-April 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence April-July 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence August-December 1975, 1962-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes earlier written materials; includes news clippings
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January 1976, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Includes older materials and follow-up letters
- Harrison Trice Correspondence February-December 1976, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes earlier written materials
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January-April 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence May-August 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence September-December 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January-October 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence October-December 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January-May 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence June-October 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence November 1982-March 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence April-August 1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence September-December 1983 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January 1984-May1985, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence June-September 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence October-November 1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence December 1985-January 1986, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence February-March 1986, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Includes an earlier published article
- Harrison Trice Correspondence April-July 1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence August 1986-February 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence March 1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence March 1987 continued (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence April-June 1987 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence June-July 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence July 1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence August-December 1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January-March 1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence April-December 1988 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January 1989-January 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence January 1990 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence February-June 1990 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence August 1990-February 1994, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Harrison Trice Correspondence Non-Dated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Drinking and Absenteeism, 1966-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Alcohol and AIDS, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Alcohol and Crime, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- University and Community Reports on Alcoholism, 1973-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Social Organization of Drinking, 1946-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Alcohol and College Students, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Alcoholics Anonymous, 1955-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Responses to Alcoholics Anonymous Programs, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Statements on Alcoholics Anonymous, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- AA Grapevine, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- AA World Directory, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Conversion to Alcoholics Anonymous, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Melvin Barger Papers on AA, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Methods for Reaching Sobriety, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- General Service Conference of Alcoholics Anonymous, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Twenty-Ninth Annual Meeting of the General Service Conference of AA, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Thirtieth Annual Meeting of the General Service Conference of AA, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Thirty-First Annual Meeting of the General Service Conference of AA, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Alternative Explanations for the Beginnings of Alcoholics Anonymous, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Second Copy of Alternative Explanations for the Beginnings of Alcoholics Anonymous, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Thirty-Third Annual Meeting of the General Service Conference of AA, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Is Alcoholics Anonymous a Religion?, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- AA Newsletters, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Memoirs of the Foundation of AA (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Forty-First Annual Meeting of the General Service Conference of AA, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Institute on Alcoholism, 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Proceedings of the Institute on Alcoholism, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  October 10-December 12 1951
- History of Alcoholism, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Canadian Council on Alcoholism, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Theories of Alcoholism, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Symptoms of Alcoholism, 1956-1970 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Alcoholism as a Disease, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Alcoholism among Men and Women, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Stages in the Alcoholic Process, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Organizational Responses to Alcoholism, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Testimony on Alcoholism, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Facts on Alcohol and Alcoholism, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- New York City Affiliate of the National Council on Alcoholism, 1972-1980 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Alcoholic Denial and its Prevention (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Alcoholism Awareness, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- General Resources on Alcoholism, 1976-1986 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- US Journal of Drugs and Alcohol Dependence and other Newsletters, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- New Careers for Moral Entrepreneurs (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Research on Adolescent Drinking, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Social Learning and Adolescent Drinking, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Alcohol and Careers, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Treating Alcoholism in Wisconsin, Indiana, and Iowa Companies (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Measuring Results in Employee Assistance Programs, 1951-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Economics of Alcohol, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- The Costs of Alcohol Abuse, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Cost-Benefit Analysis of Alcoholism Rehabilitation, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- ALCOA (Aluminum Company of America) Alcoholism Case Handling (Box 3, Folder 10)
- ALCOA Alcoholism Program (Box 3, Folder 11)
- American Cyanamid Company Program for Rehabilitation of Problem Drinkers, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- American Motors Alcohol and Drug Abuse Program, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Various Company Policies on Alcoholism, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Atlantic Richfield, Atlantic Time Products, and Audubon Hosiery Mills, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Bemis and Bell Canada, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Boston Gas and Boston Globe, 1957-1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Burlington Northern (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Western Electric, 1949-1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Colorado Interstate Corporation Program on Problem Drinking, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Alcoholism Procedure - Con Edison, 1966-1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Alcoholism Policies - Consolidated Papers, Conrail, Control Data Corporation, and Coors Container Company, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Alcoholism Programs - Corning Glass, Curtis-Mathis, Cyanide Plastics, Dearborn Dairy, Dixie Chipboard, and Du Pont, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Alcoholism Policies - Eaton Corporation, Eastman Kodak, and ESB Incorporated, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Western Electric, CareUnit, Fairchild Camera and Instrument, Fargo Foundry Steel and Manufacturing, Foote Mineral, Gage Brothers Concrete, and Galton Iron Works, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- The Alcoholic Executive (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Hamilton District Health Council Reports on Alcoholism, 1963-1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Trends in Alcohol and Drug Abuse, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- State and Federal Alcoholism Programs, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Policies for Alcoholism among Federal Employees, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Alcoholism Programs - General Electric, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Alcoholism Bulletins and Memos - General Electric, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Employee Assistance Programs - General Motors, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Includes a news clipping
- Alcoholism Policies - General Tire, Gibbs Die Casting Aluminum, Gillette, and Great Northern Paper, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Alcoholism Policies - Hazel den, Hartford Insurance Group, Henderson Clay Products, Hercules Inc., and Hewlett Packard, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Hillcrest Carpet Company, Hitchhiker Manufacturing, Horner Waldorf, and Honeywell, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Hughes Aircraft and Huron Manufacturing (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Alcoholism Policies - Illinois Bell Telephone and Illinois Central Gulf Railroad, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Alcoholism Programs - Inmont and Inland Ryerson Construction Products (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Inmont, IBM, International Harvester Company, and International Wire Works, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Alcoholism Programs: ITT, Jewel Company, and Jockey International, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Kaiser Aluminum and Chemical and Kemper Insurance, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- The Kemper Program, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Alcohol Abuse at Utah Copper Division of Kennecott Copper Corporation, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Alcoholism Policies - Lakota Products, Laurel Plastics, Lessona Corporation, Lever Brothers, Liggett and Myers Tobacco, and Laconia Shoe Company, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Alcoholism Policies - Lockheed Aircraft, Lukens Steel, Marion Power Shovel Company, Meadville Malleable, Merck and Company, and Merrill Lynch, 1967-1974 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Alcoholism Policies - The Merritt Company and Metropolitan Life, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Alcoholism Policies - Motor Wheel, Mountain Bell, The Murray Corporation, and National Homes Corporation, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Alcoholism Surveys, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Alcoholism Policies - Pete Lien and Sons, Pfizer, Pharr Yarns, PJH (Piper, Jaffray and Hopwood), Polar Telephone, and Pollak Steel, 1972- 1974 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Quaker Oats Company, PSE and G (Public Service Electric and Gas), and PPG (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Alcoholism Programs - Mobil Oil, Michigan Bell Telephone, and Minnegasco, 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Alcoholism Policies - Olin Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Employee Assistance Programs - Owens-Illinois, Peoples Gas Company, Panax Corporation, Pawtucket Manufacturing, and Penobscot Company, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Employee Assistance Programs - R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, Rumford Press, and Scovill, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Alcoholism Policies - Shell, Spencer Foods, Trimline Manufacturing, and Union Carbide, 1969-1978 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Alcoholism Policies - United Airlines, Union Pacific Railroad, and United California Bank (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Alcoholism Policies - Wine Institute, West Virginia Paper and Pulp, and Wisconsin Electric Power Company, 1955-1973 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Drinking Patterns and Alcoholism Among American Negroes, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Alcoholism Questionnaires, 1962-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Alcohol, Drugs and Arbitration, 1969-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The Plant Labor-Management Committee - Organizational Development and the Collective Bargaining Process, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Company Newsletters, 1954-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Sex, Gender and Delinquent Behavior, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Hypotheses about Deviant Behavior, 1971-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Case Studies in Occupational Deviance, 1969-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Diagnosing Alcoholism, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Aspects of Alcohol Drinking, 1968-1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Prescribed and Pleasure Drugs, 1975-1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Pamphlets on Drug and Alcohol Use, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Drug Abuse Prevention, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Factors in Drug Prevention, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Drug Policy Making, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- The Politics of Drug Testing (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Influence on Young Male Drug Use, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Drug Use in School Systems, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Early Drug Involvement Among Inner City Junior High School Youths, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Multiple Drug Use, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Responses to Drunk Driving, 1978-1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Drinking and Driving Countermeasures, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Assessing the Effectiveness of Employee Assistance Programs (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Expanding the Scope of Employee Assistance Programs (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Maryland Comprehensive Health Planning Agency - Alcoholism Subcommittee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- City Alcoholism Programs (Cleveland, Dallas, Elkins, Galton, and Henderson), 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Houston Alcoholism Programs, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- City Alcoholism Programs - Kansas City, Lincoln, and New York, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Alcoholism Policies for New York City Public Employees, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- City Alcoholism Policies - Phoenix and Seattle, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Report of the New York City Alcoholism Study, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  January 11, 1963
- U.S. Public Health Service OSAP (Office of Substance Abuse Prevention) - Grant Application Kit (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Factors in Alcohol Abuse Prevention, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Approaches to the Prevention of Alcohol Abuse, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Strategies for Minimizing Alcohol Problems, 1965-1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Swedish System for Prevention of Alcoholism, 1960-1975 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Early History of the former North American Association of Alcoholism Programs, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- The Pittsburgh Foundation Briefing Book, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Alcoholic Support Groups, 1972-1992 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Alcoholic Support Groups continued, 1956-1981 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- State Alcoholism Programs - Arizona and California, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- First Annual Report of the California State Employee Alcohol Program, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- State Alcoholism Programs - Connecticut, Delaware, and Florida, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  Includes news clipping
- State Alcoholism Programs - Illinois, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Project on Community Dynamics, Social Competence, and Alcoholism in Illinois, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- State Alcoholism Programs - Maryland, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- State Alcoholism Programs - Massachusetts and Michigan, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- State Alcoholism Programs - New York, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- State Alcoholism Programs - North Carolina, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- State Alcoholism Programs - Pennsylvania and South Carolina (and Puerto Rico), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- State Alcoholism Programs - Utah, Washington, and West Virginia, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- The Role Unions Play in Addressing Alcoholic Employees, 1966-1979 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Union Perspectives on Alcoholism, 1972-1977 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- AFL-CIO Guidelines on Employee Assistance Programs (EAPs), 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Management and Union Perspectives on EAP Policy Development, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Alliance Group of America, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Are There Only Benefits in Industrial Wellness and Employee Assistance Programs?, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- How EAPs Differ from and Resemble Job-Based Alcoholism Programs, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Organization and Ideological Factors Prominent in the Formal Launching of EAPs, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- EAPs - An Evaluator's Perspective (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Occupational EAPS - What Do They Look Like? - A National Survey, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Occupational Project - Report on Critical Tasks with their Skills and Knowledge, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- EAP Fieldguide to Counseling Styles, Strategies, and Situations, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Work and Family Systems - An Integrated Framework, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Cost Effectiveness Evaluation of Service Delivery Programs, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Alcoholism among Hospital Employees (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Evaluating EAPs (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Almaca Survey of Women Employees and Utilization of EAPs, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Factors Affecting Success of Occupational Program Clients, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Perceptions of an EAP and Willingness to Go, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Innovations in EAPs, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Issues in the World of Work, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Elements of Class Structure in EAPs, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- EAP Significance of Genders in Aftercare, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- The Relationship between Referral Types, Work Performance, and Employee Problems (Box 5, Folder 22)
- EAPs and Early Intervention, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- The Management Awareness Approach (Box 5, Folder 24)
- The Law, EAP and You, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- The University as Base for an Employee Assistance Service, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- EAPs in Theory and Practice, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- EAPS - Philosophy, Theory, and Practice, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Review and Analysis of Current Efforts in Occupational Programming, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Performance Benchmarks for the Comprehensive EAP, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Experience of EAPs with Pathological Gamblers, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- The Influence of Source of Referral, Triggering Incident and Level of Motivation on Alcoholics in EAPs (Box 5, Folder 32)
- EAP Research Then and Now, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- The Nature and Effects of an Increase in Alcohol-Related Self-Referrals in EAPs (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Aspects of EAPs, 1973-1990 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Prediction of Organization Referrals by Program Implementation Variables, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- EAPs in Higher Education, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- Occupational Alcoholism Programming in Major American Corporations, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  The 1976 Executive Caravan Survey for the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism
- Adapting Employee Alcoholism and Assistance Programs for College and University Faculty, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- The Emphasis on Alcohol Abuse in Employee Assistance Programming, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Barriers to the Initiation of EAPs, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Employee Assistance and Employee Alcoholism Programs in Major American Corporations - Similarities and Differences in 1979, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- The Core Technology and Organizational Environment of EAPs, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Structure and Outcome in Employee Alcoholism Programs, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Examination of Sex Role Responses in an Industrial Counseling Program, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- EAPs and Troubled Employees, 1972-1980 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- EAP Resources and Handbooks, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- EAPs and Career Development (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Financial Evaluation of EAPs, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Sourcebook for Evaluating EAPs, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Assessing the Service Effectiveness of EAPs, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Using Cluster Analysis to Define EAPs, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- The Changing Role of Organized Labor in Worker Assistance, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Management Styles, Perception of Drug Abuse and EAPs in Organizations, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- EAPs - Where are They Located and Whom do They Serve? (Box 5, Folder 55)
- In-House vs. Contracted-Out EAPs, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Evaluation of the Training Course for EAP Referral Agents, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- EAP Pamphlets, 1977-1987 (Box 5, Folder 58)
- EAP Pamphlets continued, 1973-1990 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  Includes a color poster; includes some Spanish language material
- EAPs - Industry News and Resources, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Promoting the Establishment of EAPs, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Evaluations of Industrial Alcoholism and EAPs, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 62)
- An Employee Assistance Program (EAP) for Professional Pilots, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Evaluation of Alameda County and Alabama EAPs, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)